If you are interested in designing an exercise program specifically for yourself my advice is to take the advice of a personal trainer if you don't have those resources, then think about what are the things that you really like to do.
If you don't like to run then don't set a running program up for yourself because you'll set yourself up for failure.
Simply find those activities that you really enjoy.
Is it dancing?
Is it swimming?
Is it walking?
Have you tried resistance training?
Those are the things that you need to think about when you design a program.
You need to also think about how many days per week can I do this program?
How long can I spend doing the program and at what intensity level am I able to work out?
Those are the three variables that you need to think about along your exercise program that you can manipulate over time.
Can you work out more times per week than when you started?
Can you go longer in your duration?
Can you increase the intensity?
If you try and stay with the same program for week after week or month after month your body is going to get used to it and say this is easy.
It started hard, it's easy and it needs more of a challenge so to avoid those plateaus find some other exercises that you might like to do and incorporate those so maybe Monday you will go for a walk, Tuesday you go for a swim, Wednesday you go for a bike ride, etc.
You really need to incorporate something that is going to challenge your cardiovascular system which is the heart and lungs, it is going to elevate the heart rate and also some resistance exercises using dumb bells or free weights.
You don't necessarily have to go to a gym but find something that you can do at home and make sure you are using proper form and techniques so that you avoid risk of injury along down the lines.
This is Alice Monsaert hoping that you can design a program for yourself to keep yourself healthy for the rest of your life.